Anjali Setlur Nagesh

114 November Drive, Harrisburg, PA * (716) 598-7155 * Email: anjalisetlurnagesh@gmail.com * LinkedIn Url:https://www.linkedin.com/in/anjali-setlur-nagesh-23934aa8/

SUMMARY

4 Years of professional experience in Front-end Development using jQuery, Angular JS(1.6), Angular 2/4/6, Node.js, Javascript, Typescript, HTML5,CSS3, Json, Bootstrap. Also, I have 1.5 Years of professional experience in Active Directory, BMC Remedy tool and User Account Management.

EDUCATION

New Jersey Institute Of Technology, Newark, NJ, USA

Master of Science in Information Systems

August 2014 - December 2015

GPA: 3.55(4)

JSSATE, INDIA
Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

September 2008 - June 2012

GPA: 3.0 (4)

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEPARTMENT OF CORRECTIONS, PA - Javascript Web Developer Consultant, USA

(Dec 2016 - present)

- Assisted Development by creating independent reusable components and packages.
- Managed development keeping in mind the business requirements and UX, Integration of components and fetching data from API.
- Developed configurable screen layouts for the enterprise level applications and worked on code generation tool, T4T template.
- Worked on CSS PreProcessors like SASS.
- Extensively used MVC Framework (Model View Controller).
- Implemented Angular features like creating custom directives, Pipes, Dependency Injection, Modules and expertise in implementing lazy loading and routing.
- Created Template Driven Forms and Model Driven Forms with built in and custom validations.
- Worked using momentJs for Date functionalities.
- Experience in cross browser compatibility testing and intellectual changes in User Experience, Responsive web design and Bootstrap.
 (Environment: AngularJs, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, Node.JS, Javascript, Typescript).

SPINO Inc, PA - Javascript Web Developer Consultant, USA

(April 2016 - Dec 2016)

- Worked with the BA's and gathered requirements, converted the requirements into UX designs. Developed and integrated the designed screens to deliver to the users under the given SLA.
- Developed the communication between the remote servers and Web Applications using Angular services and implemented CRUD operations through the HTTP methods.
- Worked with Node Package Manager.

(Environment: AngularJs, Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, Node.JS, Javascript, Typescript).

Microland Pvt Ltd- Service Engineer, Bengaluru, India

(July 2012 - March 2014)

- Performed Active Directory Housekeeping.
- Created virtual machines and monitored the status of tickets and updates regularly.
- Resolved requests and incidents through BMC Remedy tool.
- Resolved auto generated alerts from servers on Disk, CPU and memory monitoring,
- Maintained user access using Active Directory, change logging and escalation for other teams.

SKILLS

- Web technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JSON, JavaScript, Typescript
- JavaScript frameworks: Angular.JS, Angular 2/4/6, jQuery
- Server-side Languages: Node.js
- Other Tools and Technologies: NPM, Gulp, Grunt , Bower, Web pack, Angular-CLI, sql, Axure Rp, TFS
- Functional Skill Set: Requirements/Design/Test case documentation

PROJECTS

Created a Mobile Based Application Prototype (College 360 app)

• As part of system analysis design and requirement engineering course, gathered and analyzed requirements from the Software Requirement Specification (SRS) and Verification & Validation documents and made a mobile based application prototype for college 360 App using Axure RP. This application was college based and was accessed by a unique college id assigned to individual students.

Designed a Health Recipe App (UX Design)

• As part of the UX design course, my team completed a semester-long project in which I worked on a detailed analysis of the user experience of various mobile applications in a given problem space. Investigated the reasons behind success or failures of each app. We finally developed a medium fidelity prototype using Justinmind prototyping software.